握不住的她（青年查理之烦恼）
翻校:松松酱
时间轴：松松酱
小牛控咖啡馆
You can make this happen.
You're Charlie brenner.
你可以的 你是查理·布里纳啊
I think that's the problem.
这才是问题所在
You are Charlie brenner.
And who is she?
你可是查理·布里纳啊
她算哪根葱?
Just another girl working
at another coffee shop
making shit coffee.
不就是在咖啡馆打工
只会煮难喝咖啡的普通女生么
Shit coffee.
难喝的咖啡
Shit coffee. Shit coffee!
难喝的咖啡 是真难喝啊!
Can I help you?
请问需要什么?
Small coffee, please.
小杯咖啡 谢谢
Cream or sugar?
加奶油还是糖?
Oh, that'd--
that'd be great.
噢好的
Both.
都要
Dollar fifty.
一块五
Here. That's all right.
给 不用找了
Hey! Forgot your keys.
嘿! 你忘拿钥匙了
Oh.
噢
-Thanks.
-No problem.
- 谢谢
- 不客气
Wait...
等一下...
Don't I have to prove
they're mine?
我不用证明一下这是我的吗?
What happens if I'm
just saying they're mine,
but they're really not?
要是我撒了谎 拿走了别人的钥匙呢?
I mean, they are my keys.
I'm not a thief or anything.
它们是我的没错 我也不是小偷
I don't take other
people's keys, but i-i--
不会乱拿别人的钥匙 可是...
I'm just saying that you
never know these days.
这世道谁也说不好
Have a good day.
再见
What-- what's your name?
你... 你叫什么名字?
-Amber.
- 安柏
I'm Charlie.
我叫查理
Yeah, I don't mean to catch you
off guard or anything,
我没别的意思
but I just wanted to
tell you that I see you
in here all the time
就是想说 我来这儿买咖啡的时候
when I come in
to get my coffees,
总是看到你
which are really good,
and I just--
这样很好 而且我...
yeah, I think you're really...
我觉得你真的...
You're really... something.
你真的... 挺那啥的
Something?
哪啥?
Something good.
挺好的
No, obviously, i--
不对 我显然...
no, it's--
i mean, you could have
said something worse.
不 你... 还好你没说什么坏话
That's what I was thinking.
I wanted it to be...
我就是这么想的
我希望能...
Yeah. Uh...
Have a good day.
行吧 那再见了
Wait. These aren't
really my keys.
等等 这真不是我的钥匙
It's-- thanks.
多谢
-Doctor.
- 博士
Smells good.
好香啊
Mmm. Almost ready.
马上就好了
What?
怎么了?
Nothing.
没事
Isn't that that card game?
You don't need the cards.
那不是那个纸牌游戏吗?
用不着纸牌的
-Mom?
-Yes?
- 妈妈
- 嗯?
Have you ever wished
anyone was dead?
你有没有想让谁去死过?
Dead?
No, honey, of course not.
去死? 没有啊宝贝 当然没有
- Why would you ask me that?
你怎么想到问这个?
Oh, Charlie! Charlie!
噢查理! 查理!
I mean, really? Charlie!
要不要这样? 查理!
-I love you, mom!
-Steven!
- 我爱你 妈妈!
- 史蒂文
Honey, why would you
even ask me something
like that?
宝贝 你怎么问这个?
'Cause I heard dad
say it the other day.
因为那天我听到爸爸这么说了
He overheard me
on a business call.
他偷听我打电话谈业务
Yeah?
是吗?
The kid's 10.
He knows I was joking.
这家伙已经10岁了
他听得懂我是开玩笑的
Yeah, next he'll run
through the house
with six hand grenades.
下次他就会拿着6颗手榴弹
满屋子跑了
Well, he does, he does.
God forbid the boy
follow his heart.
他想这么干就这么干呗
谁也不能阻止他遵从自己的意愿
--Nice, Ross. Really. Classy.
你真牛 罗斯 干得漂亮
--Oh, wow. Brilliant. Brilliant.
好极了 好极了
-Oh! It hit the table! No! No!
-Oh. Hot potato, am I right?
- 要掉在桌上了! 不! 不要!
- 噢 还是个烫手山芋是吧?
- No!
不要啊!
Charlie, are you depressed?
查理 你抑郁吗?
You're crazy, mom.
I'm fine.
别说傻话 妈妈 我没事
Have you thought anymore
about finishing up
that application?
你就没想过写完那个申请?
That restaurant over on Vernon?
弗农的那家餐厅?
I know, I know.
Mind my own business.
I'm annoying.
我知道 我知道
别多管闲事 我太烦了
Your father called today.
你爸今天打电话来了
-What did he want?
-Who knows?
- 他要干嘛?
- 谁知道呢
I hung up before
he could launch into a speech.
我在他开始长篇大论前就挂了
-Is he all right?
-I doubt it.
- 他没事吧?
- 我看悬
That's Heather.
海瑟来了
-Oh, okay. I got it.
-You sure?
- 好的 交给我吧
- 你确定?
-Yeah. Have fun.
-Yeah.
- 当然 玩得开心点
- 嗯
-Thanks for making dinner.
-Yeah.
- 谢谢你做晚饭
- 客气啥
Oh, please, please, please!
Oh! Oh! No, no, no!
求求你放过我!
噢! 噢! 不要啊!
- Oh, so nice, you guys.
你们真是厉害死了
-Hey.
-Hi.
- 嘿
- 来啦
Are you going to brook's
tomorrow night?
明晚要不要一起去布鲁克家?
-Everyone's gonna be there.
-Oh, great.
- 大家都会去
- 好极了
Maybe I can explain
to everyone individually
that I still live at home
这下我可以告诉每个人
他们都要开公司了
when they're about to
run their own companies.
我还住在家里
Oh, come on, Charlie.
别这样 查理
They're still the same idiots
they always have been
他们都跟以前一样 除了变肥
and always will be,
just fatter.
仍旧那么傻
-What is on your face?
-No touching.
- 你脸上什么东西?
- 别碰我
Okay, okay, sorry. Freak.
I was just getting a crumb off.
行行行 对不起 怪胎
我只是想帮你擦掉面包屑而已
Come on, you should go tomorrow.
Ben's gonna be there.
明晚一起来吧
本也会去的
Oh, is Ben my lover?
干嘛 本是我男朋友吗?
You say that as if he isn't.
说得你俩不基情四射一样
Think I could bring somebody?
我带人一起去行吗?
Yeah, you can bring me. Duh.
这还用说 你可以带我啊
Who else would you bring?
不然你准备带谁?
Hey. Did Brad call?
My phone died.
嘿 布拉德打来过吗?
我手机没电了
Uh, maybe. I haven't been
picking up the phone.
可能吧 我一直没接电话
-Why not?
-'Cause I'm testing myself
- 干嘛不接?
- 我在测试自己
to see how long I can go
without modern appliances.
能忍住多久
不用现代电器
Like a caveman.
像穴居人一样
You're watching TV.
可你在看电视
I am.
是的
-Are you drunk?
-Yup!
- 你是不是喝醉了?
- 没错!
Move please.
别挡住电视
Thank you.
谢谢
Yoo-hoo! I'm home!
字体斜体我回来啦!
How was your meet today?
今天比得怎么样?
After Brad finished
the 100 meter I thought
we were screwed
布拉德跑完100米以后
我觉得我们输定了
but then Adam Smith
won the 200,
不过后来亚当·史密斯赢了200米
and Adam bedilia came in second
at 110, so we were fine.
亚当·博蒂利亚的110米栏跑了第二
所以还算可以吧
Adam bedilia?
亚当·博蒂利亚?
Yeah, he's short.
Kind of skinny, I guess.
对 很矮 有点瘦的那个
Hmm. I thought that
was Adam small.
我以为他叫小亚当
No, Adam small is small
but Adam bedilia is short.
不是 小亚当是瘦小
亚当·博蒂利亚是矮
Okay.
好吧
I spilled a whole pot
of tea at work today.
It was everywhere.
我今天打翻了一整壶茶
弄得满地都是
Are you okay? You didn't
burn yourself, right?
你没事吧? 没烫伤吧?
No, I'm fine. It was just
really embarrassing.
没有 我没事
就是超囧
Oh, there's Adam green too,
come to think of it
我想起来了
我们队里还有个亚当·格林
but he's a freshman so it's
like a whole other story.
他是新来的
跟那几个又完全不一样了
I'm pretty sure his dad's
a booster and bought him
a spot on the team.
他爸肯定是赞助人
花钱让他进了田径队
-Right.
-He's so slow.
- 是吗
- 他跑得超慢
-Hey, sorry we're late.
-Hey!
- 不好意思我们来晚了
- 嘿!
-Hey, how are you? Good?
-Good. How are you?
- 你怎么样? 挺好的?
- 挺好的 你呢?
Good. What's up, my man?
你好啊
-Hey.
-Hi.
- 嘿
- 嗨
-Hi!
-Hi. How are you?
- 嗨!
- 嗨 你怎么样?
Good.
挺好的
How was your day?
今天过得怎么样?
Good! I got my
orientation stuff today.
不错! 我今天收到入学通知了
It's our last few
weeks together.
过几个礼拜我们就要分开了
-Really makes me sad.
-I know.
- 想想就伤心
- 我明白
But we'll still see
each other during breaks.
不过放假的时候我们还能见面啊
Yeah, I know.
But do you think
we'll still be us?
是啊 不过我们还会和现在一样吗?
-What do you mean?
-I don't know.
- 什么意思?
- 说不好
I've just been
thinking a lot lately
我最近想了很多
about how much
we're gonna change
我们以后的改变
and I just hope that
my future self still likes
your future self.
我只是希望未来的我们还能互相喜欢
Okay, well, don't think
about that stuff.
好吧 别想那么远
We still have some time.
我们还有时间
Yeah, and then
the next thing you know
可是一眨眼你就成了老奶奶
you're a grandmother
and you're dead.
然后我们就天人永隔了
I don't know. I was
kind of hoping there was
something in between.
不是吧 我还希望有精彩人生呢
Well, there's always
track and field.
还好田径场永远都在
- Mm.
是啊
Just come out and ask her, man.
你就直接下去问她
She just serves coffee.
不就是个咖啡小妹么
-Shitty coffee at that.
-Terrible coffee.
- 煮的咖啡又难喝
- 难以下咽
-It's awful. The worst.
-Yech. She doesn't even deserve
- 是我喝过最难喝的了
- 嗯 给我上那么难喝的咖啡之后
to talk to me after serving
coffee that horrendous.
她都不应该跟我说话
She deserves to die for it.
她应该以死谢罪
Oh, hi.
噢 嗨
Hi.
嗨
Last time I was in here
you were mopping too.
上次我来的时候你也在拖地
Actually, I was sweeping.
我那天在扫地
That's right. Yeah, sweeping.
说得对 扫地
Yeah, you were sweeping,
come to think of it.
我想起来了 上次你是在扫地
Hey, listen, I didn't mean to
weird you out or anything
a couple of days ago.
听我说 那天我没别的意思
It's fine.
不要紧
You from--
where are you--
where are you from?
你是... 你是哪里人?
-From here.
-Oh, yeah? Me too.
- 本地人
- 是吗? 我也是本地人
Oh, nice.
挺好
You in school, or...
你还在上学吗 还是...
Uh, well, I'm going to
college in the fall.
今年秋天就要去上大学了
-Uh-huh.
-Yeah, I'm going to nyu.
- 是吗
- 嗯 去纽大
That's a good one.
I've heard of that.
好学校啊 我听说过
Uh, New York university.
Listen, I was just--
纽约大学 我刚刚...
okay, have a nice day!
好了 再见!
So? She's coming
to the party, right?
怎么样? 她会来的吧?
Eh, whatever.
随便吧
You know, she served me
this latte last week--
it just was gross.
上次她给我做了一杯拿铁
太难喝了
-Can we just get out of here?
-Yeah.
- 赶紧走行不行
- 行
For here or to go?
堂食还是带走?
To go.
带走
What was that all about?
刚才什么情况?
Just some guy.
就一个男的
You don't hide from
just some guy, so...
你平时可不会躲着一个男的 所以...
I have a boyfriend, so...
我有男朋友...
So it's not cheating just
to talk to the poor bastard.
跟那个可怜人聊聊天也不算出轨啊
Was I being mean?
I'm sorry, I'm just...
我刚才是不是太小气了?
不好意思 我只是...
I don't know.
I'm not really good
with stuff like that.
说不清 我不擅长这种事
Stuff like what? Being nice?
什么事? 对人友善?
Thank you, sir.
谢谢 先生
I hope you enjoy your beverage,
and have a wonderful day.
请享用您的饮料 并拥有愉快的一天
Yeah. Whatever.
嗯 行吧
You see? Nice.
看见没? 友善
- Okay. Listen. Stop.
字体斜体这样 听我说 别走
- Baby.
- -Hey, can you get that?
- 字体斜体亲爱的
- 嘿 能开下门吗?
How's it going, Jack?
近来如何 杰克?
It's going.
凑合吧
-Hey.
-Hi.
- 嘿
- 嗨
Be gentle. I'm queasy again.
轻点 我又犯恶心了
Hey, do you mind if we go to
that new Italian place tonight?
今晚去那家新开的意大利餐厅怎么样?
I gotta get my carbs in
for tomorrow.
我明天比赛 得多吃点碳水
Well, I thought we were going to
Amanda's sister's thing tonight.
我还以为今晚要去阿曼达的姐姐那儿呢
No, I can't.
I have to run tomorrow.
我去不了 明天要比赛
I don't know. I was
excited about tonight.
那怎么办 我还挺想去的呢
Come on. Don't be selfish.
拜托 别这么自私嘛
Hey, we're going to some party
if you wanna come with us.
嘿 我们要去参加派对
要是想来可以一起
He doesn't wanna go.
他不想来的
Says who?
谁说的?
Okay, the address is on my desk,
but it's not your type of thing.
好吧 地址在我桌上
不过你不会感兴趣的
I'll be the judge of that.
感不感兴趣我说了算
Great.
好极了
See ya.
走了
- Tell me what to do.
敢对我指手画脚
Ooh, somebody's smoking.
Here, just keep going straight.
某人今天超辣啊 这边 直走
Can you hold it? Thanks!
麻烦等一下 谢谢!
What's wrong with you?
你怎么了?
What? Nothing.
什么? 没怎么啊
No, something's
definitely wrong.
不对 你绝对不对劲
I told you you shouldn't
have had that second burger.
我说吃一个汉堡就够了吧
-You're literally sweating.
-Are you gonna come watch me
run tomorrow?
- 你都流汗了
- 你明天会来看我比赛吗?
-Or are you at the coffee shop?
-I'll come.
- 还是要打工?
- 我会来的
What happened with that girl
from the coffee shop?
你跟咖啡店那个姑娘怎么样了?
I don't know what
you're talking about.
我不知道你在说什么
The one you were
practically stalking.
你一直跟踪的那个姑娘
Ben said he waited
for like an hour for you to
finally say something to her
本说他差不多等了你一个小时
你才跟她说上话
and you totally pussed out.
到头来你还是怂了
I really, really, really don't
wanna talk about this right now.
我现在真心 真心 真心
真心不想谈这件事
What's wrong with you?
你到底怎么了?
Nothing. I'm just...
没事 我就是...
Just trying to concentrate
on giving myself an aneurysm.
在集中精神让自己长血管瘤
You're so weird.
真是个怪人
-You okay?
-I'm fine, yeah.
- 没事吧?
- 没事
-Excuse me. You are sexy.
-Thank you.
- 不好意思 你好性感啊
- 谢谢
-What's your name?
-Thank you.
- 你叫什么名字?
- 谢谢
Oh, you're sexy.
No, you are sexy.
你好性感啊
不 你好性感啊
-Hey, what's up, Todd?
-Oh, same ol', same ol'.
- 嘿 来啦 托德
- 还是老样子
Just another chapter
in the book
依旧走在对于美女无休止追求的
I like to refer to
as the endless pursuit
of sweet, sweet ass.
人生旅途上
You live a menial
existence, my friend.
活得够卑微的啊 朋友
You have no idea.
No idea, buddy.
那你是不知道啊 兄弟
I'll be right back.
失陪一下
Ladies, the Todd is here,
have no fear.
女士们 帅哥托德在此 别害怕
I know we do duets, right?
我们可以二重唱 对吧?
-Hi!
-Hey!
- 嗨!
- 嘿!
Together at last.
终于又见面了
-How you doing?
-How are you, Ben?
- 你好吗?
- 你怎么样 本?
-Jazzin'. What's up?
-Well...
- 不错 怎么了?
- 那个...
-Is that who I think it is?
-Yeah. Don't ask.
- 那是不是我想到的那个?
- 对 别问了
That guy's one of the fastest
runners on the college circuit.
他可是大学巡回赛跑得最快的选手之一啊
Who?
谁?
What do you mean who?
That's Brad Parker.
什么谁? 那是布拉德·帕克啊
Are you blind? Look who's coming
out right there behind him.
你瞎了吗? 看不见跟着他出来的是谁?
Oh, man. You need a drink.
噢我去 你得喝一杯了
Hi.
嗨
What was your name again?
你叫什么来着?
-Uh, Charlie.
-Charlie.
- 呃 查理
- 查理
I'm Amber.
我叫安柏
I know. I know.
我知道 我知道
Well, I just wanted to say hello
after what happened back there.
我就是想来打个招呼
刚才在电梯里有些尴尬
Oh, you didn't have to.
你不用这么做的
You should've told me that
two minutes ago.
那你两分钟前就该告诉我的
You would've saved me
the walk across the roof.
我就不用穿过整个屋顶了
So is that your boyfriend?
那是你男朋友?
Mm-hmm.
嗯
Isn't he some big fast runner
or something?
他是不是跑步健将什么的?
A big track star?
短跑明星?
Yeah, but don't tell him that.
He won't be able to fit his head
through the door.
嗯 不过别告诉他
不然他的尾巴能翘上天
How about you?
You with that girl?
你呢? 那是你女朋友?
Heather? No, just friends.
海瑟? 不是 我们是朋友
Our mothers met in lamaze class.
我妈和她妈在产前辅导班认识的
It was one of those
eternal damnation type deals.
我跟她是从小互怼到大的那种关系
Yep. Shoot.
是吧 糟了
What?
怎么了?
Check this place out.
这地儿可以啊
Yeah, Charlie, this is
my cousin, Jeff.
查理 这是我表哥 杰克
Hey, nice to meet you.
嘿 很高兴认识你
Holy shit. It's the popcorn man.
我的神啊 你是那个卖爆米花的
He works at the
movie theater on doffin.
他在多芬路的电影院上班
He gives me a hard time
when I go in to play
the candy crane machine.
他不让我玩钓糖果机
We have a policy at the theater
about people who refuse
to buy tickets.
电影院有规定
不买电影票不能玩糖果机
-Wait, the revival theater?
-Uh-huh.
- 等等 就是那家放老戏剧的影院?
- 对
-You work there?
-Yeah.
- 你在那儿上班?
- 对
You should get a job there.
你应该去那儿找份工作啊
Don't tell me. He's the manager.
别跟我说 他是经理
No, I'm only assistant manager
so not really. I can't--
不 我就是个经理助理 没法...
I can't, uh--
yeah.
我没法... 行啊
Yeah, you should--
okay, come in this week
and I'll see what I can do.
你应该... 好吧 这周来找我
我想想办法
-Deal.
- 说定了
-That's a deal.
-It is. A deal.
- 就这么定了
- 好的 一言为定
-Deal.
- 说定了
Excuse me!
我的天呐!
- No, no, no.
-Shh!
- 不行 不行 不行
- 嘘!
- Okay.
-You are sexy.
- 好吧
- 你好性感啊
You are drunk.
你喝醉了
I'm not.
但我没醉
Hey, Todd, come here.
嘿 托德 过来
-So, uh...
-Hey, Todd!
- 嘿 托德!
- 那个...
You didn't finish telling me
about that thing earlier.
刚才那事儿你还没说完呢
-What thing?
-The surgical procedure
- 什么事?
- 特别重要的
that was really important.
Come on.
那场手术 快来
-So...
-Hey, can we head out please?
It's getting kind of late.
- 所以...
- 嘿 我们能走了吗? 时间不早了
Hey, Brad, this is Charlie.
布拉德 这是查理
-Hey, what's going on, Charlie?
-Hi.
- 你好啊 查理
- 嗨
You're that guy.
你就是那个谁啊
What guy?
哪个谁?
-Oh, gross. Who barfed?
-That dude!
- 好恶心啊 谁吐了?
- 他!
This guy did it, right?
Everybody, it was him.
是他吐的 对吧?
大家都看见了
You wanna clean that up, man.
你要打扫干净吗?
-Come on. Sorry!
-Clean that up!
- 快走 抱歉!
- 打扫干净!
Party foul, man.
派对上出丑了 哥们儿
-Can we go now? Can we go?
-Yeah. Yeah.
- 能走了吗? 现在能走了吗?
- 好 走吧
Here you go.
来吧
-I got ya.
-Yeah.
- 有我呢
- 嗯
Put him in the back.
把他放在后座
-Thank you.
-Uh-huh.
- 谢谢
- 没事
-I appreciate it.
-We're gonna go in the car now.
- 非常感谢
- 准备上车了
-Watch the head.
-Watch his--
- 当心头
- 当心...
-thanks for your help.
-Yeah, no worries.
- 谢谢你帮忙
- 不客气
Make sure he gets some water.
给他喝点水
-Don't throw up.
-Oh god.
- 别又吐了
- 天呐
Oh, how are your shoes?
你的鞋子没事吧?
Well, ironically enough, I asked
for the vomit-covered model
说来讽刺 我买鞋的时候就想要防吐款的
when I bought them,
but they were all sold out.
可惜都卖完了
-Ah.
-Yeah.
- 啊
- 是啊
Come on, honey.
I've really gotta go.
走啦 亲爱的 我真得回去了
-I'll see you. Okay.
-I'll see you.
- 回见了
- 再见
-You look so happy!
-Uh-huh. Uh-huh.
- 你怎么这么开心啊!
- 是啊 是啊
-Ah, it could've been worse.
-Not really.
- 这结果还算可以吧
- 可以什么啊
You assholes.
I thought you left me.
你们这俩混蛋
我还以为你们把我丢下了呢
Almost! Almost got away clean.
差一点! 差一点就摆脱你了
Hey, Charlie, who was that
cute girl you were talking to?
查理 刚跟你讲话的那个漂亮姑娘是谁啊?
-Hmm?
- 嗯?
What?
干嘛?
What did I say?
我说错话了?
森格尔电影院
Thanks.
谢谢
Enjoy.
观影愉快
One cheeseburger.
一个芝士汉堡
-How's your mother?
-Fine.
- 你妈最近怎么样?
- 还行
And you? Still cooking?
你呢? 还做饭吗?
Mmm. Here and there.
嗯 偶尔做
My little boy.
The four-star chef.
我的宝贝儿子 四星大厨
Are you depressed, Charles?
You don't seem like yourself.
你抑郁吗 查理斯?
你看起来状态不好
What are you talking about?
You haven't even seen me
in two years.
说什么呢 你都两年没见我了
Two years isn't so long.
两年也不算太久
You're still working
in this shit hole.
你不还在这鬼地方上班么
You know what you need?
You need a career.
你知道你需要什么吗?
一份事业
-You need a career.
-I have a career.
- 你才需要一份事业
- 我有事业啊
Private detective.
我是私家侦探
-You're a private detective?
-Private detective.
- 私家侦探?
- 没错
I really think
it's my true calling.
我真心觉得这是我毕生的使命
I haven't gotten
hired yet or anything
虽然还没人雇我
but the whole thing
just feels right.
不过我觉得这条路没错
I've been a fast learner.
我学东西一向很快
So how long you in town for?
你准备在这儿待多久?
Huh? A couple days.
A week or two at the most.
哈? 几天吧 顶多一两个礼拜
You know, I'm staying
at the Bryson's motel
off highway 65
我就住在65号高速公路旁边的
布莱森旅馆
and I was just wondering...
Maybe I could stay with you.
Think your mother would mind?
我在想... 能不能跟你去住
你妈会介意吗?
I'm a little short
on cash right now.
我手头有点紧
There's no way.
不可能
Charlie, I'm your dad.
Talk to her.
查理 我是你爸啊
你去跟她说说
There's no way.
不可能
Just talk to her.
跟她说说看嘛
--There's no way!
不可能!
He said it was only
gonna be a few days.
他说他就待几天
That's what he said
thirty years ago and
i ended up married to him!
30年前他就是这么说的
结果呢 我就嫁给他了!
He could stay in my room.
可以让他睡我房间
--Charlie, no.
查理 不行
Mom. Please.
妈 求你了
-Ah, look at that.
You still got it.
-Yeah.
- 你还留着它呢
- 嗯
Let me see that.
Bring it on over here.
拿过来给我看看
Ninety-five.
95号
Last time Orlando
won the series.
还是上次奥兰多队拿冠军的时候
Remember when
i got that for you?
还记得我给你弄到它的时候吗?
I'm gonna go sleep
on the couch downstairs.
我去楼下的沙发睡了
No, stay with me up here!
别啊 跟我一起睡上面吧!
Too crowded.
太挤了
If three's company,
how can two be a crowd?
都说三人成伴 两个人怎么会挤?
Your mother mad?
你妈生气了?
Just try
and stay out of her way.
She'll get over it.
你别去招惹她 她的气会消的
Okay.
好吧
Wouldn't be the first time.
你也不是第一次惹她生气了
It smells like donkey here.
这儿的味道跟牛圈似的
You didn't have to come.
我又没拽你来
Is that that girl again?
这不是那天那个姑娘吗?
Oh, my god, you're sick.
You're sick! I'm gonna
call the police!
我的妈呀 你害相思病了
相思病! 我要报警了!
Yeah, well, good.
At least in jail
行啊
I won't have to hear
your voice ringing in my head
every three seconds.
起码进了监狱
我不就不用成天听你叨叨叨了
Why don't you just go
and say hello?
你干嘛不去跟她打个招呼啊?
I would feel creepy.
那会吓到她的
You are!
你是挺吓人的!
I'm not! I'm...
我才不! 我...
Jesus, what's your problem?
天呐 你什么毛病?
Just messing with you.
我跟你闹着玩啦
You should go and talk to her.
你应该去找她聊聊
You're like the greatest
guy ever, Charles.
你是我见过最好的人 查理斯
--She has a boyfriend
who is a track star.
她有男朋友 短跑明星
Oh, whatever.
那又怎样
Damn.
我了个去
That is fast.
真跑挺快啊
-You all right?
-Mmm.
- 你没事吧?
- 嗯
Yeah, it's my stomach again.
胃又疼了
Maybe you're pregnant.
你可能是怀孕了
I'm not pregnant!
我才没有怀孕!
How do you know?
你怎么知道?
Because I'm careful.
因为我很小心的
God, can you imagine?
Brad would kill himself.
天呐 要是我真怀孕了
布拉德会自杀的
There's a sign you're in
a healthy relationship.
你们俩的关系真是健康极了
Hey. What's up?
嘿 你最近怎么样?
Nothing.
没怎么样
I just wanted to stop by
and say hello.
我就是顺便来打个招呼
I was in the neighborhood, so...
正好在附近 就...
Okay. Yeah, I'm really
busy right now.
好吧 我现在特别忙
It's getting
really hectic, so...
生意太好了 所以...
Mmm.
嗯
-Right.
-Yeah.
- 好吧
- 嗯
See you later.
回见
Okay.
好
--Take care.
保重
Now that wasn't
too awkward or anything.
你们俩还真是一点也不尴尬呢
I want a shower
just witnessing that.
我都想去洗眼睛了
Charlie!
查理!
Hey, I get off
at 6:00 tomorrow.
我明天6点下班
I'm gonna meet
a friend downtown,
然后要去市区见朋友
but maybe you
wanna walk me there?
If you're in the neighborhood?
你能陪我走过去吗?
如果你正好在附近的话?
Yeah.
好啊
You're the man.
你就是她看中的男人
Oh, yeah.
People like you.
噢 耶
大家都喜欢你
Girls like you.
姑娘们都喜欢你
And they would if you
knew more of them,
如果你认识更多姑娘
她们肯定会喜欢你的
but you live with your parents.
You're a loser.
可是你还跟爸妈住在一起
简直是个窝囊废
No. Come on!
不行 加油!
Come on, Charles!
振作起来 查理斯!
You're a good, humble guy.
你是个谦虚的好男人
Admitting you're humble
while staring at yourself
in the mirror
看着镜子承认自己谦虚
is probably the least
humble thing you can do
大概是你做过最不谦虚的事了
but you just gotta relax. Relax!
不过不用紧张 放轻松
You live a completely
normal life.
你的生活完全正常
You just gotta have
a little bit of pride.
只要你自信一点
Have some pride.
自信一点 自信一点
Have some--
have some...
自信... 自信...
Have some pride!
自信一点!
Oh, hey, hon. Sorry.
Forgot my towel on the bed.
不好意思 儿子
我忘拿毛巾了
I walk almost everywhere.
Helps me think.
我基本上去哪儿都用走的
走路能帮助我思考
What do you think about?
你平时都思考些啥?
I guess I think
about all I could get done
if I stopped thinking.
思考那些如果我不思考了
就能做成的事
- Oh.
-What?
- 噢
- 干嘛?
No, that's original.
没有 这我还是头一次听说
I mean, even if it is
annoyingly self-defeating.
No offense.
虽然这种想法挺自暴自弃的
无意冒犯
But, no, I just
thought you were gonna
pull out some crap
我还以为你会扯些别的
about how all you think about
are cute animals or world peace.
说你在思考小动物或者世界和平
Or something like that.
诸如此类的
Oh, you mean you
didn't catch that?
你没懂我的意思吗?
That little pretentious bit
was supposed to be a metaphor
刚刚那番做作的说辞
就是来比喻
for how much
i like cute animals.
我有多喜欢小动物
-And world peace.
- 以及世界和平
In fact, I want world
peace for all animals.
事实上 我希望所有动物
都生活在和平的世界里
And I'm doing this Noah's
ark project next month if
you wanna help.
我下个月还要做个诺亚方舟
你愿意的话可以来帮忙
It should only take 40 days
and 40 nights or so.
估计花个40天40晚就差不多了
Right. After 40,
your ark's built, no?
是哦 40天之后呢?
方舟就造成了?
Or 80, yeah, but who's counting?
也可能要80天 不过谁会算这日子呢?
- I'm not counting.
反正我不会去算
You been here before?
你来过这儿吗?
Yeah. Yeah, a few times.
嗯 来过几次
When I was a kid it was my dream
to have my own restaurant.
我小时候的梦想就是开一家自己的餐厅
Not anymore?
现在放弃了?
Uh, I don't know.
我也不知道
Can you cook?
你会做菜吗?
Uh... that's what they tell me.
别人说我做得还行
I wish I could cook.
I can't even make cereal.
真希望我也会做菜
我连麦片都泡不好
-Or coffee.
-Asshole.
- 咖啡也煮不好
- 混蛋
Wait. So how come you work
at a movie theater instead
of a restaurant?
可是你为什么在电影院上班
不去餐厅工作?
Sensitive subject?
这是敏感话题吗?
No, not really. I just...
不算是 只不过...
I don't have all
the answers yet.
我自己也还没想明白
Where do you live?
你家在哪儿?
I live off Charles street.
查理斯路那边
-Oh, yeah.
-With my cousin. Yeah.
- 哦是吗
- 我和表哥一起住
Well, my family's in Florida.
They moved last year
because of my dad's work,
家人都在佛罗里达
因为我爸去那边工作 他们去年都搬过去了
but I decided to stay here
so I could finish high school,
不过我决定留在这儿
上完高中
and I could also stay with Brad.
也能继续和布拉德在一起
How long have you been together?
你们俩在一起多久了?
Almost four years. Yeah.
快4年了
Now that I think of it,
i don't think I've been single
since grade school.
现在想想 我从小学开始就一直有对象
It doesn't surprise me.
意料之中
You know what's
strange about you?
你知道你这人怪在哪儿吗?
On one hand,
you're painfully shy
你既害羞得烦人
and on the other hand,
you say these things that
i don't think I could ever say.
又能说出一些我永远说不出口的话
-Things like what?
-Like what you just said.
- 什么话?
- 就像你刚才说的
I mean, it's not a bad thing.
You're just different.
这也不是什么坏事
只不过你和别人不一样
Different.
不一样
You know what I mean.
你懂我的意思的
Different. No, I can live
with that. Different.
不一样 没事 我能接受
不一样
Different.
I'm gonna say... maybe.
我觉得... 可能吧
Maybe. Yeah.
可能吧
This is it. Thanks for the walk.
到了 谢谢你陪我走过来
Oh, no, no. Anytime.
不客气
Would it be out of line
to ask for your number?
我知道这有点唐突
能给我你的电话号码吗?
How about you give me yours?
把你的号码给我怎么样?
Here you go.
给
Okay. Cool. I had fun today.
好了 我今天很开心
Yeah, me too.
We should do it again.
嗯 我也是
我们改天应该再出来走走
Yeah, um...
那个...
Okay, I don't know how
to say this without sounding
like an ass, but--
我不知道这话要怎么说
才能不那么难听 可是...
oh, no. You have a boyfriend
who you love, and we are only
gonna be friends. I get it.
你有深爱的男朋友
我们只能做朋友 我懂的
There's no expectations.
我不会抱有期待的
-Sweet. Okay.
-Really.
- 那就好
- 真的
I'll call you.
我会打给你的
Hey.
嘿
Who was that?
那是谁啊?
Oh, just a regular. We were both
walking in the same direction.
一个店里的老顾客
我们正好顺路
He's kind of cute.
挺帅的啊
-You think?
-Yeah, kind of.
- 是吗?
- 嗯 蛮帅的
Oh, this is a bold
choice right there.
这个选择很大胆啊
Do you have any truffle salt?
有松露盐吗?
I'm going out for a bit.
我出去一下
What are you staring at?
你看什么看?
I'm sorry. Looking at you
makes me feel young again.
不好意思 看着你让我觉得又年轻了
-How long are you staying for?
-Just a little while.
- 你还要在这儿待多久?
- 用不了多久了
I made arrangements
to be out during the day,
so I won't get in your way.
今天白天我有约
所以不会碍着你的事的
-Good. Bye, honey.
-Bye.
- 很好 再见亲爱的
- 再见
Won't even look at me.
她都不看我一眼
Just give her a break.
你别烦她了
One, please.
麻烦来一个
Application, that is.
职位申请表
Nine-fifteen, ten-fifteen.
九点十五 十点十五
This guy can't seem
to hold a job for more
than two months.
这家伙估计干不到两个月就得走人
Just give him a chance.
I'll vouch for him.
给他个机会吧 我来做担保
You owe him a favor?
你欠他人情?
No, just one of those things.
没有 反正有点事
Cryptic. You'll train him?
神神秘秘的 那你来培训他?
All right you little prick.
Our journey ends here.
好了你个小傻逼
我们来做个了断
Today, your ass is mine.
今天你要死在我手上了
-Hey!
嘿!
-Shit! What?
操!  干嘛!
You want the job or not?
这工作你还干不干了?
All right.
好吧
So, popcorn. Easy, huh?
你看 爆米花 很简单吧
But if they want butter,
you give two squirts
in the middle, three on top.
但是 如果有人要黄油
就在中间挤两泵 顶上挤三泵
Any more, and we have to
charge 20 cents extra.
再要加的话 就得多收20分了
Did you know that emus
are the only animals
你知道鸸鹋是唯一一种
that willingly have sex
with humans when seduced?
被引诱后会跟人性交的动物吗?
Think about that.
想想看
-Are you thinking about it?
-No, not really.
- 你在想吗?
- 没有
Think red, think red, think red.
红色 红色 红色
验孕棒
Hey, this is Brad. Sorry I can't
get to the phone right now.
嘿 我是布拉德
抱歉我现在接不了电话
Hey. Hey, Brad, it's me. Amber.
嘿 布拉德
是我 安柏
Give me a call.
给我回电
Hi, this is Leslie. I can't
get to the phone right now,
嗨 我是莱斯利
我现在接不了电话
so leave a message
and I'll get back to you.
请留言 我会尽快打给你的
Hey, Leslie, it's Amber.
Call me.
嘿 莱斯利 我是安柏
给我回电
Amber, hey.
嘿 安柏
How are you?
你好吗?
I'm okay. Okay.
还好 还好
What are you doing tonight?
你今晚有什么事吗?
Tonight I'm...
Just making some dinner and--
今晚我... 就是做晚饭然后...
you are? What are you eating?
是吗? 你们晚饭吃什么?
Um...
那个...
So how do you two
know each other?
你们俩是怎么认识的?
-Oh...
-From my work.
- 噢...
- 在我上班的地方认识的
I work at a coffee shop.
我在咖啡馆打工
Oh, no kidding! Me too.
是吗! 我也是啊
When I was a kid
i worked at a coffee shop.
我小时候也在咖啡馆打工
Here we go.
又来了
We were known as the best
cup of Joe in Brooklyn.
我们店的咖啡是布鲁克林最出名的
"You want good Joe?
It's the place you gotta go."
"要喝好咖啡 就来我们店"
You grew up in Georgia.
你是在乔治亚州长大的
I know where I grew up.
我知道我自己在哪儿长大
I'm just trying to spice up
the story a bit. Jesus Christ.
这不是让故事更有趣一点么
真是的
-This is really good.
-Oh, thanks.
- 这些菜真好吃
- 谢谢
Kid's a genius in the kitchen.
这孩子可是个厨艺天才
Like you would know.
说得跟你知道似的
Amber, let me show you
what Charlie won
安柏 我给你看看查理几年前
in a big state-wide
cooking competition
a couple of years ago.
在全州的大型烹饪比赛获的奖
It was city-wide. I didn't win.
I just came in second.
就是个全市范围的比赛
我也没赢 只拿了个第二
Mom!
妈!
Oh, wow!
哇欧!
- How about it, huh?
- -Yeah.
- 厉害吧
- 厉害
It's got his name on it
and a medal.
上面绣了他的名字
还有一枚奖章
That's nice.
不错啊
And one of the judges, Trevor--
其中一位评委 叫崔弗...
-i forget his last name.
-Trevor vanier.
- 姓什么我给忘了
- 崔弗·范尼尔
Well, he writes for this major
cooking magazine in New York.
他给纽约一本有名的烹饪杂志写文章
He came up to Charlie afterwards
and told him that he thought
赛后他找到查理 说查理是他见过
he was one of the most talented
amateur chefs he'd ever seen.
最有天赋的业余厨师之一
- He gave me a medal.
- -Yeah.
- 所以他给了我奖章
- 对
-How about it?
-Yeah.
- 怎么样?
- 嗯
And then what?
那后来呢?
Well, he gave Charles
his number.
他把电话号码给了查理斯
And said he was all ears
if he ever wanted to talk.
还说只要他想谈 他随时恭候
But I never called. We know.
Thank you, mom. I'm an asshole.
但我一直没打 我们都知道
谢谢妈妈 我就是个混蛋
Language!
别说脏话!
-Steven Jacobs!
-Put that down.
- 史蒂文·雅各布斯!
- 把枪放下
You don't tell my son
what to do.
轮不到你教训我儿子
Probably learned
the behavior from you.
有其父必有其子
- What did you say?
-What? No, nothing.
- 你说什么?
- 嗯? 什么也没说
-Guys.
-Steven, put it down!
- 各位
- 史蒂文 把枪放下!
Well, don't be so hard
on the kid. He's just a kid.
别难为他 他还只是个孩子啊
You make the rules
in your own house!
我们家的事你别管!
Steven, come on.
Give it to me.
史蒂文 乖 把枪给我
Hey. Not the lady.
Just take me.
嘿 放过女士 让我来
- Oh, that's nice. Both of you.
你们俩真是厉害死了
That's very nice. That was
academy award-winning material.
太厉害了 简直能拿奥斯卡了
Amber, I'm sorry, sweetie.
安柏 让你见笑了 亲爱的
Come on.
别闹了
I'm really sorry
about what happened in there.
That was so embarrassing.
刚才真是对不起
太丢脸了
What is it?
出什么事了?
I can't believe I'm telling
you this. I hardly know you.
我居然会把这事告诉你
我甚至都不了解你
Took a pregnancy test.
我验了孕
It was negative, but...
没中 可是...
The whole idea of it made my
whole life flash before my eyes.
那个念头让我的一生在眼前闪回
You ever get nervous
about the future?
你担心自己的未来吗?
Me?
我吗?
No.
不担心
I have a great set-up.
I'm fifty-five years old.
我对未来有很棒的规划
等我到了55岁
I work
at a shitty movie theater,
and I live at home.
在一家破烂电影院上班
和爸妈住在一起
Well, I don't understand why.
我不明白
You're so talented. I feel like
you could have a job at any
restaurant you wanted.
你这么有才华
应该想去哪家餐厅都不成问题
Oh.
噢
I'm glad I met you, Charlie.
认识你真好 查理
My friend is having a party
Tuesday if you wanna go.
我朋友周二要开个派对
你愿意的话可以来
He just took the bar,
so it's a little celebration.
他刚参加了律师考试
算是庆祝吧
Tuesday night. I'm hanging out
with my friend Leslie
and Brad that night.
周二晚上 我要和我朋友莱斯利
还有布拉德出去逛逛
-Well, you can bring them.
-Yeah?
- 你可以带他们一起来啊
- 真的吗?
Yeah, even bring Jack
too if you want.
也可以叫上杰克
I think I accidentally told him
about it anyway.
我反正不小心把派对的事告诉他了
Right! I totally forgot
you got him that job.
对哦! 我都忘了你帮他找了工作
It's no-- no big deal.
小... 小事一桩
Well, thank you.
谢谢你
Okay, so Tuesday.
It's a date.
行 那就周二 说定了
Right. Tuesday it is.
好 周二见
-Okay.
- 好
- 嗯
-Do you need anything?
-No, I'm good.
- 要帮你拿什么吗?
- 不用
But come on in.
Sit down. Let's talk about it.
进来吧 坐会儿 我们聊聊
What's with your
mother's husband?
你妈的老公什么毛病?
I don't wanna
get into this with you.
Russ is a good guy.
我不想跟你讨论这个
罗斯人挺好的
There's no reason
to get uptight about it.
我没必要跟他置气
You know...
那什么...
How's your girlfriend?
你女朋友没事吧?
-Amber. She's just a friend.
-Amber.
- 安柏 我们只是朋友
- 安柏
There's no need to keep things
from your old man.
跟你爸就不用藏着掖着了
I saw the way
she was looking at you.
我看见她看你的眼神了
-No, you didn't.
-Actually, yeah, I did.
- 不 你没看见
- 我的确看见了
And it gets to my point.
她的眼神说明了一切
Maybe you have to be
more aggressive with her.
也许你应该更主动点
Sometimes, no matter
how hard it is,
有时候 无论多难
you just gotta
step to the plate.
你都要直面挑战
That sounds like a bad t-shirt.
跟短袖上印的烂标语似的
Hey, hey, hey.
等一下
What?
干嘛?
I spoke with a gentleman
from New Orleans today.
今天一位新奥尔良的男士找到了我
Looks like I booked
my first assignment.
看样子我的第一笔生意有了
-Really?
-He's gonna put me up
and everything.
- 真的吗?
- 他要雇我做事
Your old man is staying
at the riverview Plaza.
你爹要住到河景广场去了
- Well, that's great.
那太好了
Thinks his wife is cheating
on him with his boss.
他觉得他老婆背着他
和他老板乱搞
Lot of screwed up
people out there.
多得是过得一团糟的人啊
Like you?
像你一样?
Life is complicated, Charles.
生活是很复杂的 查理斯
Things aren't always
as black and white
as they seem.
任何事情都不像表面上那样非黑即白
And you of all people
should know that,
你应该最明白这一点
especially after what
you been through.
尤其在你经历了那一切之后
Night.
晚安
Charlie...
查理...
I love you.
我爱你
Love you too.
我也爱你
-Thank you.
-Cheers, guys.
- 谢谢大家
- 干杯
Red wine doesn't even count.
红酒哪算酒啊
It's sophisticated.
喝红酒显得老练
It is sophisticated.
喝鸡尾酒才显得老练
All the cool people--
自信的人都...
she's coming.
Like this. It looks better.
She's coming in.
她来了 端着这个 好看点
她进来了
-Hey.
- 嘿
You've met Brad
and this is Leslie.
你见过布拉德的
这是莱斯利
-Hey.
-Nice to meet you, Leslie.
- 嘿
- 很高兴认识你 莱斯利
I need a drink.
Hi, buddy, good to see ya.
我要喝酒
哥们儿 你好啊
You guys want something?
你们喝点什么?
Just water's good. Thank you.
白开水就行 谢谢
Water?
白开水?
-How you doing? It's Brad.
-Heather.
- 你好 我是布拉德
- 我是海瑟
-Hi, I'm Leslie.
-Heather.
- 嗨 我叫莱斯利
- 我是海瑟
Good to see you.
很高兴认识你
You with the thing?
你也是来这个的?
-The party? Yeah.
-Yeah.
- 派对吗? 对的
- 嗯
I'm a friend of Charlie's.
我和查理是朋友
You know Charlie?
I know Charlie.
你认识查理? 我也认识他
I work at the movie
theater with him.
我是他在电影院的同事
I'm really into pop culture
and stuff, so it's cool. Yeah.
我特别喜欢流行文化 它们太酷了
It's a pretty cool gig.
You know, it's all right.
这份工作也很好 挺好的
-Cool.
-Yeah.
- 真好
- 是啊
You want a drink?
你要来一杯吗?
Oh, don't worry
about it. I got it.
别担心 我自己来
Oh, cool. Whiskey on the rocks.
好啊 威士忌加冰
No, I'm actually gonna
get myself one.
不是 我要自己调一杯
Whiskey on the rocks.
威士忌加冰
I just can't believe
that you're finally done.
简直不敢相信你真的做到了
Don't jinx it. It's not like
i passed yet.
先别说得太早 结果还没出来呢
But if I do, you should consider
coming to New York with me.
不过如果我过了
你应该考虑跟我一起去纽约
It's not that easy to just
pick up and leave.
我又不能说走就走
Why? Are you the mayor?
为什么? 你是市长啊?
What do you have going on here
that's so important?
这儿有什么要紧事让你脱不开身啊?
You can't let fear of failure
run your life, man.
别让对失败的恐惧支配你的人生 兄弟
That's got to say something good
about taking risks.
你跟她的事就说明冒险的必要性了吧
It's funny. She's the only girl
i ever felt charming around.
有趣的是 她是唯一一个
让我觉得自己有魅力的女生
-You're not charming.
-That's the thing. I know.
- 你没什么魅力
- 是的没错 我知道
Sorry. I don't know
what I was thinking.
抱歉 我想什么呢
Hello?
有人吗?
This is kind of fun
for an old people party.
这派对也太无聊了
Mm-hmm.
嗯
Hey, I think that guy Charlie's
pretty nice, by the way.
话说回来 我觉得那个查理不错诶
Yeah, he's nice but he's got
some serious problems.
嗯 他人挺好但他的问题很严重
I mean, he means well
but he's just lost.
他心地善良 但对生活没有目标
Since when are
you so judgmental?
你什么时候变得这么刻薄了?
I'm not. It's just...
我没有 就是...
Okay, he wants to own
a restaurant or something,
他想开家自己的餐厅
but he's so screwed up that
he won't even talk about it.
但他太丧了
甚至不愿意提起这个话题
And that's the thing.
He's a really good cook,
问题在于 他厨艺很棒
but he won't take it seriously.
可他却不认真对待
It's sad.
太悲哀了
I don't know. I don't think
i could ever be with someone
like that, you know?
我说不好 感觉我不会跟那种人在一起
Well, lucky for you
it's not an option.
幸好你有男朋友了
Yeah.
是啊
Where you going?
你要去哪儿?
I'm picking up
my son from school
去学校接儿子
-you want company?
-No.
- 要我陪你吗?
- 不要
What do you say you
let me take you out
明天我带你出去吃早餐
to breakfast tomorrow to
thank you for letting me stay.
作为你让我住在这儿的感谢怎么样?
I didn't let you stay.
If it were up to me,
我没让你住在这儿
如果我能说了算
you wouldn't even be allowed
in the state.
我就禁止你进入这个州
Yeah.
是哦
Sam, I feel regret
every day for what I did.
萨姆 我对自己的所作所为一直后悔
I've missed you for a long time.
我想你很久了
And I know you don't
believe me, but it's true.
我也知道你不相信我 但我是真心的
-We had some good times.
-Yeah, and then you cleared out
- 我们曾经很快乐
- 是 然后你偷走了我的存款
my bank account and left me
alone with our son.
丢下了我和儿子
And I always meant
to pay you back. Always.
我一直想要补偿你们
But things don't always pan out
the way you want them to.
但总没法事事如意
-Why did you come back here?
-I have a job waiting for me
- 你为什么回这儿来?
- 我在新奥尔良有份工作
in New Orleans.
I wanted to see you guys.
也想来看看你们
And I had nowhere else to stay.
我也没别的地方可去
Yeah, that sounds more like it.
这个理由才像真的
Well, I got myself into
a bit of a pickle.
我碰上了点麻烦
I owe some people some money.
欠了别人一些钱
Are you ever gonna grow up?
你什么时候能长大?
I don't know. I'm trying.
不知道 我在努力
I want a fresh start.
我想要一个全新的开始
You broke my heart so badly,
i didn't think I was gonna
be able to live.
你把我伤得那么深
我一度觉得要活不下去了
Did you know that?
你知道吗?
Yeah, I did.
我知道
I get a letter or something
every couple of years
for two decades,
你隔几年才寄一封信之类的
这么过了20年
and then suddenly one day
you show up like you're a guest
in some old friend's house?
然后突然 你就像拜访老朋友一样
大摇大摆地进了我们家?
Please. I'm gonna be late.
求你了 我要迟到了
You're never gonna
forgive me, are you, Sam?
你永远不会原谅我了对吧 萨姆?
I don't remember you even
asking for forgiveness.
你从来就没有求过我的原谅
I'm asking you now.
我现在就乞求你原谅
No, no! Come on!
I had you!
不! 搞什么啊!
我都抓到了!
I-- I had him.
我都抓到他了
-Had who?
-The white whale
to my captain ahab.
- 抓到谁?
- 亚哈船长的白鲸
I had him and now he's gone.
我抓到他又被他溜走了
-Are you drunk?
-No!
- 你是不是喝醉了?
- 没有!
Yes.
是的
So what's the deal with
your friend Heather, man?
She's pretty hot.
你朋友海瑟什么情况?
她很性感诶
You mind if I try
to move on in?
我能主动进攻吗?
Move on in?
主动进攻?
You trying to get a date or
infiltrate a foreign brigade?
你是想跟她约会还是渗透进敌方阵营?
Shit, man, I'm just asking.
我靠 我就问问而已
You need to relax.
你别紧张啊
What's with you?
You depressed?
你什么情况? 抑郁了?
I'm fine, okay?
Thank you. Thank you.
我没事 好吗?
多谢关心
- It's Amber, isn't it?
是因为安柏吧?
It is, huh?
我没说错吧?
Wanna know how I figured it out?
想知道我怎么发现的吗?
'Cause you're the first person
in a long time who's gone
out of their way for me.
因为这么长时间以来
只有你帮我找了工作
Being that I'm not
exactly prince charming,
我知道自己不是白马王子型的
I'm gonna go ahead
and guess it's not about me,
所以你肯定不是想帮我
so my money's on Amber.
所以我押安柏
You trying to impress
her or some shit.
你是为了讨好她
But the bitch of it is,
she's got a boyfriend
但可气的是 她有男朋友了
who's in better shape,
is better looking,
has a great future.
比你壮 比你帅 而且前途无量
You don't know what
you're talking about.
胡说八道什么呢
All right, man, that's cool.
行吧 你就嘴硬吧
You think he's better looking?
你觉得我没他帅?
Oh, yeah, I mean
look at the guy.
那可不 你看他
He's got a square jaw,
his dick probably has
a six-pack. I'd do him.
下巴方正有力 大屌粗壮无比
换我我也会扑上去
Okay! All right.
Enough. Jesus.
打住! 可以了别说了 天呐
You asked.
是你非要问
You missed a spot. Just there.
那个角落没扫 那里
How's it going?
你最近好吗?
It's been a little while.
I've missed you.
好久没见 我很想你
Yeah, I've just been busy.
Things are hectic around here.
我最近挺忙的 家里事情可多了
-What's wrong?
-Nothing.
- 怎么了?
- 没事
I just heard you talking
in the bathroom at the bar.
我听见你在酒吧洗手间里说的话了
I heard what you said about me.
关于我的事情
-It's not what it seemed like.
-Yes, it is.
- 我不是那个意思
- 你就是那个意思
But that's fine.
不过没关系
It's how you feel.
I can handle it.
那是你的真实想法
我能接受
I'm so sorry.
I don't blame you
for being mad.
真对不起 你生气我不怪你
I'm not mad. I'm embarrassed.
我没有生气 就是觉得丢脸
And mad, obviously. I'm mad.
当然也生气 我很生气
I think you're really great.
That's why I said those things.
我真的觉得你很棒 所以我才那么说的
Obviously.
显而易见
Don't be like that.
你别这样
What I was trying to say
is that I don't get you.
我的意思是 我不理解你的做法
I mean, you have so much
going for you. It's frustrating.
你浪费了才华 太让人失望了
You're smart and you're nice.
And you're cute. You're funny.
你聪明 善良 可爱 还搞笑
I'm not funny.
我不搞笑
Well, maybe not on purpose.
就算不是刻意的吧
What?
什么?
Oh, hey guys.
Towel. On the bed.
嘿 孩子们
毛巾 忘在床上了
That was a mistake.
那是个错误
No, I know. I'm really sorry.
我知道 真抱歉
-Okay.
- 好吧
- 好的
Okay. I'll talk to you soon.
回头见
-Okay.
- 好的
- 好
I don't normally do this
type of thing, you know?
我一般不会做这种事的
No, i--
i don't usually either.
我也不... 不常做这种事
I'm sorry I said that stuff.
抱歉我说了那些话
Did you ever go to
cooking school or anything?
你上过烹饪学校吗?
Oh, I went to college,
but I never finished.
我上了大学 但是没毕业
Why not?
为什么?
Why won't you talk to me?
为什么不愿意告诉我?
I was home for the summer
after my junior year.
大三的暑假我回了家
And Ben and I were
on our way back
from some party.
我和本从一个派对出来
Don't remember what we
were talking about.
忘了我们当时在聊什么
This car...
一辆车...
The headlights of this car
just came out of nowhere.
亮着大灯不知从哪儿蹿了出来
What happened?
Were you drinking?
然后呢? 你们喝酒了吗?
No.
没有
No. The girl who was
driving the other car was.
没有 开那辆车的女生喝了
Julie Redding.
朱莉·瑞丁
She just ran the red light,
她闯过红灯
and I tried to get out of
the way but I just couldn't
react in time.
我试图让开她的车 但是来不及了
Was she okay?
她还好吗?
It's...
真是...
It's amazing.
真是神奇
People say these things
happen so fast and they do.
别人都说车祸就在瞬间 确实如此
One second you're living
your life and the next...
上一秒你还在过自己的人生 下一秒就...
Nothing's the same. I don't even
remember myself before that.
世界都变了 我甚至记不起
那一刻之前的我是什么样的
Not really.
记不清了
Think about myself back then,
it's like thinking about
somebody else.
回忆当时 好像在回看别人的人生
I tried to go back to school,
but I was all screwed up,
我试着回学校 但我已经彻底崩溃了
so I came home.
And I was only supposed
to be here for a minute,
所以就回了家
本该就待一会儿
but one day became a week,
week became a month,
a month became...
可是一天变成了一周
一周变成了一个月 一个月变成了...
Yeah, it was the devil's deal.
就像是和魔鬼的交易
I could have eternal comfort,
but I had to trade in all
my drive. And I took it.
我可以获得永久的舒适生活
但必须交换我开车的权利 而我接受了
-It's not true.
-It is true. It is.
- 这不是真的
- 这就是真的
But it's okay.
不过也没关系
You were right about me.
I'm scared.
你说得没错 我就是害怕
我害怕
You don't think I see
what's happening
all around me?
你以为我看不到周围的一切吗?
Don't think I see the world
moving forward every day?
看不到世界日新月异的变化?
I'm terrified. I'm terrified
that I'm so content
我恐惧 我恐惧自己对生活的知足
and terrified that I'm so not.
也恐惧自己的不满足
Does that make any sense?
你明白我的意思吗?
You know, I never told Brad
that I took that pregnancy test.
我没把验孕的事情告诉布拉德
That's all right. I mean,
it would be one thing
if it were positive.
没关系啊 反正也没中
Okay, but the point is
i should be able to tell
him everything.
可关键是 我应该对他完全坦诚的
Especially something like that.
尤其是这种事情
And I can't.
可我做不到
That's okay.
没关系
You told me.
你告诉我了啊
I really like you.
我真的好喜欢你
I should go.
我该走了
Where you been?
你去哪儿了?
Out with Brad.
跟布拉德出去了
Well, that's funny. 'Cause
he's been calling here all
night looking for you.
奇怪了 他一整晚打了好多电话来找你呢
You leading a double
life, Pinocchio?
你过双重生活吗 匹诺曹?
Aw, come on.
别这样啊
It's cool. People consider me
shady too, believe it or not.
这有什么关系 人家也觉得我行动可疑啊
So I've still been thinking
about your friend Heather.
我还在想你的朋友海瑟
Oh, yeah?
是吗?
Can I get her number?
能把她的号码给我吗?
Well, I should probably
ask her before I give it out.
我得先征求她的同意才行
Don't be such a bitch.
别那么小气啊
I'm sorry. I didn't mean that.
不好意思 我不是那个意思
Oh, how's--
how's Amber?
安柏... 最近怎么样?
That's funny. She asked the
same thing about you last night.
有意思了 她昨晚也问了我你的情况
Oh, that is funny.
What did you tell her?
这么巧? 你怎么说的?
Said you were all right.
我说你挺好的
Crawling up my list
little by little every day,
popcorn man.
我越来越喜欢你了 卖爆米花的
Great news!
那太好了!
Charlie!
查理!
What's that number?
把她号码给我
You drink a lot, huh?
You get sick all the time?
你很能喝啊 你一直生病吗?
You're being rude.
你怎么这么没礼貌
No, I find it makes
me feel better.
不是 喝酒能让好受点
All right, let's cut to the
chase. What's your story?
行了 言归正传
说说你的故事?
-My story?
-Yeah, your dude situation.
- 我的故事?
- 对 你的情史
Okay, uh, well I'd say
pretty standard.
好吧 我的情史很普通
I've been in a whole bunch
of dead end relationships,
et cetera, et cetera.
我谈了不少男朋友 都没结果
等等等等
I'm a romantic.
我是个浪漫主义者
But I think co-dependency
is pathetic.
但我觉得交互依赖症太悲哀了
So I just keep
my distance unless the guy's
totally worth it.
所以除非真的遇上值得的人
不然我都和他们保持距离
Noted.
了解了
How about you?
那你呢?
Uh...
呃...
I don't really date.
我不怎么约会
I was engaged a little while
back but I got left two weeks
before the wedding, so...
前段时间我订婚了
然后在婚礼前两周被甩了...
Oh, wow. Really?
噢 真的吗?
She said that some day
I'd understand and then
she hung up.
她说总有一天我会明白的
然后就挂了电话
Did you ever understand?
你后来明白了吗?
Nope. No.
没 没有
Wow. I can't believe you were
so close to getting married.
真不敢相信你差点结婚了
Yeah. Well, close only counts
in hand grenades, right?
说得像我躲过了手榴弹一样
You ever speak to her?
你有再找她聊过吗?
Uh, no, sir, I do not.
没有 没再找她
That makes sense.
可以理解
Well, I don't believe
in real closure anyway.
我不相信人真的能彻底放下
It's like having a last meal
before an execution.
就像行刑前吃最后一餐也不能解脱
What, you know that 'cause
you were executed?
因为你被处死过?
Chris? Thank you.
克利斯? 谢谢
No. I'm sorry.
没有 不好意思
I was being nice.
我只是想对你友善一点
Okay, Jack, are we ever gonna
get to a point in the night
好吧 杰克 今晚你能摘下那副
where you take down that
"I'm obviously an insecure
asshole" wall? Or should I go?
"我明显就是个缺乏安全感的混蛋"的面具吗?
还是我现在就该走了?
'Cause I know that
guys like you do this,
我知道你们这种人常干这种事
but you're making me
wonder why you called
me in the first place.
但你让我怀疑 你一开始为什么要找我
Okay, um, I'm gonna go.
I'm sorry.
行吧 我先走了 抱歉
Hola
雷猴
"Hola" means "hello," dickhead.
那是"你好"的意思 蠢货
Right.
对哦
Something on your mind?
你有心事?
Yeah, I'm just overwhelmed.
嗯 我不知道该怎么办了
Do you wanna talk about it?
要聊聊吗?
Is it Brad?
是关于布拉德吗?
-Hi,
-hi.
- 嗨
How's it going?
你最近怎么样?
It's good.
挺好的
Can we talk?
我们能谈谈吗?
So what's wrong?
出什么事了?
Okay, here's the thing...
好吧 是这样...
I'm going to school in
a few weeks and I have
a lot to figure out.
还有几个礼拜我就要去学校了
还有很多事情我没想清楚
-I know.
-Do you?
- 我知道
- 你真的知道吗?
What is happening right now?
现在是什么情况?
I never should've gotten
myself into this position
in the first place.
我一开始就不该让自己陷入那种境地
I don't think we
should talk anymore.
我们不要再联系了
I'm sorry. I have to go.
抱歉 我先回去了
Amber...
安柏...
That day, those keys
i said weren't mine...
那天我说那串钥匙不是我的...
I was just so nervous.
是我一时太紧张了
I've been having to break in
to my house for the last month.
这一个月来我都是翻墙回家的
Hey, fellas.
嘿 小伙子们
Steve-O. I have a question
for you. Don't lie to me.
小史蒂文 我问你 老实交代
-You like playing video games?
-Yeah!
- 喜欢玩游戏机吗?
- 当然!
-Is that arcade on
government still open?
-Uh-huh.
- 市政府那边的游戏机房还开着吗?
- 开着
All right, I want you two guys
to go on down there
我请你们去那儿
and get some games in on me.
玩游戏机
That job in New Orleans
came through, and I ran into
a little bit of cash, so.
新奥尔良的工作谈成了
所以我手头有点钱了
Okay, take it easy there, pal.
I just had this washed.
别激动 小朋友
我这西服刚洗的
All right, go celebrate for me.
好了 去为我庆祝吧
About time I made someone's
day around here, huh?
也是时候由我来让别人开心开心了
Yes! Come on!
太好了! 走吧!
What's wrong?
你怎么了?
I'm just dealing with
some stuff right now.
我在想事情
Like what kind of stuff?
想什么事情?
You know. Anxiety?
焦虑
Rejection. Inferiority.
Paralysis. Character issues.
Moral issues.
拒绝 自卑 瘫痪
性格问题 道德问题
Life stuff.
思考人生
I've never been
the bad guy before, you know?
我从没做过坏人
But I love you.
可我还是爱你
I love you too, buddy.
我也爱你 老弟
- Ow! Jesus, Steven!
要死啊 史蒂文!
警车
Come here, honey.
过来 宝贝
Charlie...
查理...
What happened?
出什么事了?
I was out running errands,
and I came home to this.
我出去办了点事
回来就成这样了
Where's dad?
爸爸呢?
The neighbors said they saw him
our front with a moving truck.
邻居看见他在我们家前面
开了一辆货车
Do you have any idea
where he can be reached?
你知道他去哪儿了吗?
No.
不知道
I'm sorry, mom.
对不起 妈妈
It's not your fault, honey.
这不怪你 宝贝
"Dear Chucky.
"亲爱的查查
"I'll return it all.
You have my word.
"我向你保证
我会把这些都还回来的
"Just make sure your mother
doesn't get too mad.
"别让你妈太生气
I know deep down
she understands. I love you."
我知道在她内心深处会理解我的
我爱你"
Are you serious right now?
来真的吗?
-What's your problem?
-Nothing.
- 你怎么回事?
- 没怎么
All right.
行吧
Brad! You okay?
布拉德! 你还好吗?
Charlie? What are
you doing here?
查理? 你在这儿干嘛?
Oh, my god.
天呐
It's a bad fracture.
骨折很严重
Shouldn't be career ending,
but his season's over.
不至于葬送他的运动生涯
但是这个赛季是没戏了
What the hell happened?
到底出了什么事?
Uh, it was an accident.
We were racing--
那是意外 我们在赛跑...
-you were racing?
-We were, you know--
he was...
- 你们俩赛跑?
- 我们... 他...
I was being an asshole.
是我犯浑
How have you been?
你最近好吗?
-Other than this, obviously.
-Other than this?
- 除了这件事 很明显
- 除了这件事?
You've been on my mind.
我一直在想你
I don't-- do you think
this is a good time?
我不... 你觉得现在说这个合适吗?
-No. No.
不 不
No, but I feel like it's
the only time I'm gonna
get to see you again.
不合适 但我觉得以后再也见不到你了
When are you leaving for school?
你什么时候去学校?
My dad's coming to
get me next week.
我爸下周来接我
Okay, well, I have to
get back to Brad.
好了 我得去看布拉德了
Yeah. No, of course.
Tell him I'm so sorry.
嗯 好的 帮我向他道歉
I will.
好的
Hayden.
海登
No, no, no, no!
不是吧 不是吧!
Got it!
抓到了!
Got it.
我抓到了
Does it feel weird?
拄拐难受吗?
I had crutches when I was nine.
我9岁的时候也拄过
What's your deal
with that guy Charlie?
你和那个查理什么关系?
Nothing.
没关系啊
Do you like him?
你喜欢他吗?
Yeah, I like him.
He's my friend.
喜欢啊 我们是朋友
But do you like him?
但你喜欢他吗?
-Yeah, sure.
-Do you like him, Amber?
- 当然了
- 你喜欢他吗 安柏?
What, do you think
I'm some kind of idiot?
你把我当傻叉吗?
How could you do this to me?
你怎么能这么对我?
So you don't love me anymore?
你不爱我了吗?
I don't know. Things are
confusing right now.
我不知道 我现在脑子很乱
Look, this type of shit
just doesn't happen.
恋爱不是这么谈的
Okay? You can't just fall out
of love with someone.
你不能说劈腿就劈腿
That doesn't happen.
不能这样
You love him?
你爱他吗?
No, but...
不爱 可是...
I don't know, I...
我不知道 我...
I feel like I'm losing my mind.
我觉得我快疯了
Have you slept with him?
你跟他上床了吗?
No! How could you
ask me such things?
没有! 你怎么能问我这种问题?
-What do you want me to say?
-I want you to tell me--
- 你想让我说什么?
- 我想让你告诉我...
what do you want me to say?
Tell me what you want me to say,
and I'll fucking say it!
你想让我说什么?
告诉我 我就说给你听!
I want you to tell me you don't
give a shit about that guy,
我想让你告诉我
你一点也不在乎他
who, by the way, put me
in goddamn crutches!
那个让我摔断腿的人!
I just need to take a breath.
我只想喘口气
I feel like I haven't taken
a real breath in a long time.
我觉得这么多天以来都快窒息了
You've gotta be
kidding me right now.
开什么国际玩笑
I'm sorry. I don't know.
对不起 我不知道
I know you don't know.
You've said it 15 times already.
我知道你不知道
你都说了15次不知道了
Okay, I just...
好吧 我只希望...
I just want things to be
okay between us.
希望我们俩能好好的
Okay? That's all I want.
好吗? 我就这点要求
They're not okay!
我们俩不好!
What? You think this
is okay right now?
你觉得这事儿就这么过去了?
You think I'm okay?
我觉得无所谓?
Let me guess.
You don't know.
让我猜猜 你不知道
Hmm? You don't know.
你不知道是吧?
Yeah, you let me know
when you do, okay?
等你知道的时候再找我吧
Brad.
布拉德
How's it going?
你还好吗?
At least I've got a good book.
至少还有本好书
I'm gonna get our stuff back.
我会把我们的东西拿回来的
It's all right.
We're insured--
没关系的 我们有保险...
no, it's not all right.
不 有关系
You know where your dad is?
你知道你爸在哪儿?
Charlie!
What are you doing here?
查理! 你怎么来了?
Come on in.
进来吧
-How'd you know I was here?
-You told me.
- 你怎么找到这儿的?
- 你自己说的
Oh, right.
哦对
How's that job going,
by the way?
对了 你的工作怎么样了?
Oh, I didn't get it. They
went with another guy
with more experience.
没谈成 他们找了个更有经验的人
What can you do, right?
我能怎么办呢
So how come you're
still staying here?
那你怎么还能住在这儿?
I sold your mother's
television to get the room.
我把你妈的电视卖了付的房费
So looking to staying
at the riverview Plaza!
我太想住在河景广场了!
I just figured
i owed it to myself.
我觉得我应该犒赏自己
-At least I'm honest.
-Come on, you're not honest.
- 起码我很诚实
- 得了吧 你才不诚实
I got something for you.
我有东西给你
Put it on. Put this on.
You're gonna love it.
穿上 快穿上
你一定会喜欢的
-Dad. Dad.
-It feels great. Now come on.
- 爸 爸
- 质感可好了 快点
Please. Just try it on
for the old man.
拜托 为了你爸穿一次嘛
Look at you. Come here.
瞧瞧你 过来
All right?
怎么样?
There you are.
看看你自己
This is what it's all about.
这才是人生的意义
You're a class act.
一表人才
I'm gonna write your mother
a check as soon as I get
back on my feet.
我一搞到钱 就把支票给你妈
Double what I owe.
两倍奉还
Besides, that lawyer husband
of hers, he can buy her
anything she wants.
再说了 她那个律师老公
什么都买得起
It's not just about her.
What about me?
你不只欠她的 我呢?
-Come on, have some compassion.
-Oh, fuck you, dad!
- 拜托 同情同情我嘛
- 去你妈的 爸!
Fuck you!
我去你妈的!
I really got myself into
a jam this time, Charles.
我这次真的遭难了 查理斯
I was gonna get hurt if i
didn't pay these guys back.
如果我还不上钱 他们就要教训我
So you hurt everyone else.
And when does it stop?
所以你就伤害其他人?
什么时候才是个头啊?
You know, you've got
problems too. Yours are
even worse than mine.
你的问题也不少 而且比我严重
Now what the hell
are you talking about?
你到底在说什么?
I know about your girlfriend.
I know she got an abortion.
我知道你女朋友的事
她去堕了胎
I can only imagine what
you're going through.
真想不到你们有多难过
-What are you talking about?
-You don't have to hide
things from me.
- 你在说什么啊?
- 你没必要瞒着我的
I mean, I know
you don't want me
in your business,
我明白你不想让我插手你的生活
but I had to do
some training for the job
但我得为这份工作练习练习
which, for the record,
i should've gotten
而且我声明
这份工作本该归我的
and I just followed her around.
I mean, she seemed as good
a subject as any.
我就跟着她走了走
她看起来没什么问题
And I also did a little work on
Benny. Tell him congratulations
on the bar exam.
我还调查了一下小本
祝贺他通过律师考试
He didn't get his scores yet.
他还没拿到成绩呢
No, yeah, he did. He did
really well. I'm proud of him.
他过了 考得很好
我为他骄傲
I couldn't help myself.
我控制不住
Look, there's no harm no foul.
I put the envelope, sealed it,
done, sent it off to him.
没有伤害就不算犯规
我把成绩单放回信封 封上后寄给了他
He didn't get it yet?
他还没收到?
No, that's for you to keep.
不 你留着它吧
-Where's the furniture?
-That's for you to keep.
- 家具在哪儿?
- 留着吧
Where's our furniture?
家具在哪儿?
It's at a storage place.
在一个仓库里
-I'm taking it back with me.
-No. No.
- 我要把它们带回去
- 不 不要
-Yes.
-No.
- 我要带回去
- 不要
No, Charlie, please.
Just until I'm back on my feet.
求你了 查理 等我搞到钱
I am giving you this chance,
dad. Do the right thing.
我是给你机会 爸
走正途吧
Just until I'm back on my feet.
只要等我搞到钱就好
Charles. Go on. Go on.
查理斯 别这样 别这样
-Bye.
-Go on.
- 再见
- 别这样
--You understand?
你理解我的吧?
You know, I'm starting to think
i might be depressed.
我开始觉得我真的抑郁了
-You're all right.
-Get off me, asshole!
- 你才没事
- 别搞我 混蛋!
Watch the-- focus.
看路... 集中精神
I really think you should
come with me to New York
if I pass the bar.
我真的觉得 如果我过了律师考试
你应该跟我一起去纽约
You could use a break
from all this shit.
暂时逃离这堆破事
Maybe I will.
我也许会跟你去
-Really.
-Mm-hmm.
不开玩笑
Ah, damn. Now I really
hope I passed.
我去 现在我真的希望能过了
Trust me on this one, okay?
You passed.
信我一次好吗? 你过了
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
对不起 对不起
Roses? Can you get
any more stereotypical?
玫瑰花? 你能更老套一点吗?
Well, you just answered that.
我有答案了
I've been chasing this little
bastard for a long time.
我追这个小混球很久了
I finally caught up to him,
but the thing is,
我终于抓到了他 可问题是
I kind of wish I hadn't.
我又有点希望我没抓到他
Once I captured his beautiful
ass, I realized there was no one
there to share him with.
当他优美的身躯躺在我手心
我才发现没有人可以和我分享
Wow. You really are insane.
你真是疯了
Yeah.
对
I'm not good
with this kind of shit.
我不擅长这一套
But, Heather, I like you.
I think you're cool, you know?
但是 海瑟 我喜欢你
我觉得你很酷
And kind of pretty and...
还挺漂亮...
That is to say,
i think you're pretty.
应该说 我觉得你很漂亮
Exceedingly so.
非常漂亮
I'm sorry about
being a dick before.
抱歉我上次犯浑
And I know that I have issues.
我知道我有很多毛病
I also know that just knowing
doesn't make it okay.
也明白光知道问题所在没有用
But I think that's a first step.
但我觉得这是迈向成功的第一步
So...
所以...
There.
给
Give me that.
把糖给我
崔弗·范尼尔
纽约市第五大道790号
- Hello?
-Trevor?
- 喂?
- 崔弗吗?
- Yep.
-It's Charlie brenner.
- 对
- 我是查理·布里纳
I'm from this--
well, I was in this...
我来自... 我之前参加了...
Charlie. Charlie.
Charlie brenner!
查理 查理
查理·布里纳!
Yeah, I remember
exactly who you are.
How are you, son?
我记得你 你好吗 孩子?
Good. I'm good.
Actually, I'm moving.
我很好 我要搬家了
I'm moving to New York.
我要去纽约了
It goes right in there.
放在那边吧
Hey. Can I talk to you?
嘿 我能跟你谈谈吗?
Listen, I appreciate
everything you've done for me,
感谢你一直以来对我的帮助
but I'm moving to New York
with a friend of mine.
不过我要和朋友去纽约了
I'm ready to start
a new chapter.
准备开始一段新生活
-You're not mad?
-No.
- 你不生气吗?
- 不生气
You didn't seem to have
the right passion for this job
anymore anyway.
反正你对这份工作也没什么激情
I'm bored. Can we close
this bitch up already?
好无聊啊 能把这破电影院关了吗?
First...
首先...
Take care
of the ladies' shitter,
Mr. assistant manager.
去把女厕所扫了 经理助理先生
Yeah?
真的吗?
Get to it.
上手吧
Nice!
太好了!
And that right there?
That's passion.
看见没 那才叫激情
Charlie! Hey.
查理! 嘿
Oh, hey.
嘿
I'm just picking up
Jack from work.
我正要去接杰克下班
Yeah, I was just with him.
What are you guys doing?
嗯 我前面还和他在一起
你们准备干嘛去?
Amber's having her goodbye
party tonight at cow fiend.
安柏今晚在小牛控咖啡馆
开告别派对
Do you wanna come?
要一起来吗?
No, I've got a lot
of packing to do,
不了 我还有很多行李要收拾
but you guys have fun.
你们好好玩
-Are you sure?
-Yes.
- 你确定吗?
- 确定
-All right.
- 好吧
- 好
-I'll call you later.
-Okay.
- 回头联系你
- 好的
-Bye.
- 再见
I'm not pregnant.
我没怀孕
-Amber!
-Hi!
- 安柏!
- 嗨!
-Hi. We made it.
-Hey.
- 嗨! 终于赶上了
- 嘿
Thank you.
谢谢
-How are you?
-Good.
- 你好吗?
- 挺好的
-How are you?
-I'm good.
- 你呢?
- 我也挺好
Oh, I got a job.
In New York.
我找到了一份工作 在纽约
-Wow.
-I'm gonna be an assistant chef
- 哇欧
- 去市中心一家新开的餐厅
in a new restaurant downtown.
做总厨助理
That's amazing.
太棒了
It's pretty...
Out of nowhere, but good.
算是... 突然冒出来的机会
但是不错
It's a step in the right
direction, or in any
direction at least.
是朝着正确的方向迈出了一步吧
也许不正确但总归是迈出去了
How's Brad's leg?
布拉德的腿怎么样了?
I hope it's okay.
I mean, I don't know.
希望没事了吧
我也不知道
We've taken some time off.
我们决定冷静一段时间
I have a lot to figure out.
我有很多事需要想清楚
-Look, I want you to know--
-i-i-- I do know.
- 我希望你能知道...
- 我都知道
I'm going through a lot.
Maybe more than you know.
我经历了很多困难
可能比你知道的要多
I don't wanna get into it,
but... it's been tough.
我不想细说 但是... 很艰难
Maybe I'll see you around.
也许我们后会有期
In New York or something?
到了纽约之后?
Yeah. I'd like that.
嗯 可以啊
Give me your phone.
把你手机给我
So this is my new number,
这是我的新号码
and one of the digits
might be off, I think.
其中一个数字可能错了
So I'll just take that
as a very clear hint.
这个暗示很明显了
I'll see you.
回头见
Okay.
好的
Well, I guess that's it, huh?
你真的要走了
Better late than, never, huh?
迟做总比不做好 对吧?
I'm gonna miss you more
than you'll ever know, son.
我会非常非常想你的 儿子
-Oh, I love you, Charlie.
-Love you too.
- 我爱你 查理
- 我也爱你
You're gonna be great.
你一定能做得很棒
We'll see.
走一步看一步吧
I already do.
肯定没问题的
Thanks, dad.
谢谢爸爸
-Bye!
-Bye! Love you!
- 再见!
- 再见 爱你哦!
-You too!
-Bye!
- 我也爱你们!
- 再见!
Bye! Make good pasta!
再见! 多做点好吃的哦!
Oh, that's so nice, Steven.
好极了 史蒂文
You okay?
你没事吧?
Yeah, I'm just taking a breath.
没事 就是喘口气
What are you thinking
about over there?
你想什么呢?
Oh... lots of things.
噢... 很多东西
Mostly about cute animals
and world peace.
主要在想小动物和世界和平
You're a strange guy, Charlie.
You know that?
你真的是个怪人 查理
你知道吗?
Not so strange.
Maybe just a little different.
不算太怪 也许是有点不一样吧